If you see only one movie this year... you ought to get out more often.
The Naked Gun 2½: The Smell of Fear is a comedy,
crime film directed by David Zucker.
Bumbling lieutenant Frank Drebin is out to foil the big boys in the energy industry,
who intend to suppress technology that will put them out of business.
Lt. Frank Drebin, played by Leslie Nielsen.
Jane Spencer, played by Priscilla Presley.
Ed Hocken, played by George Kennedy.
Nordberg, played by O. J. Simpson.
Quentin Hapsburg, played by Robert Goulet.
Dr. Meinheimer / Earl Hacker, played by Richard Griffiths.
The Naked Gun 2½: The Smell of Fear is a 1991 American crime comedy film serving as the sequel to the 1988 film The
Naked Gun: From the Files of Police Squad!, and the second installment in The Naked Gun film series.
The film stars Leslie Nielsen as the comically bumbling Police Lt.
Frank Drebin of Police Squad!.
Priscilla Presley plays the role of Jane, with O.
Simpson as Nordberg and George Kennedy as police captain Ed Hocken.
The film also features Robert Goulet (who previously made a "special guest star" appearance on Police Squad!) as
the villainous Quentin Hapsburg and Richard Griffiths in a dual role as renewable fuel advocate Dr.
Meinheimer and his evil double.
Zsa Zsa Gabor and Mel Tormé have cameo roles.
David Zucker returns from the first entry as
director and screenwriter of the film.
Jim Abrahams and Jerry Zucker serve as executive producers for the film and receive writing credit
due to their contributions to the first entry of the series and the Police Squad!
television series.
However, neither contributed to the screenplay for the film.
The film was a box office success, grossing $192 million against a budget of $23
million, making it the most commercially successful of the series.
It received positive reviews from critics, though some
concluded it to be inferior to its predecessor.
A third installment in the series, Naked Gun 33⅓: The
Final Insult, was released in 1994.
The film explores themes of usa president, washington
dc, usa, the white house, police, parody.
The tone is lighthearted.